# Michael Copland

**८** 07799 627 475

**✓** mjbcopland@gmail.com

in mjbcopland

nibcopland ?

#### Overview

As a full-stack developer, I strive to approach problems with a holistic and pragmatic attitude but still enjoy exploring finer details of complex solutions; I love digging into open-source code and understanding how things work, and try to incorporate everything I learn into future endeavours.

I have a particular fondness for TypeScript, React, and GraphQL, but I also have experience with a range of other technologies spanning multiple disciplines with recent experience in Java and Python, cloud deployments on AWS, and UI design systems, all supported by standard practices and tooling such as CI/CD, Webpack/Babel, Docker, and Kubernetes.

### Experience

Software Engineer

July 2020 – December 2022

Layer.ai

Full-stack development at an early-stage startup with significant ownership of multiple aspects of the codebase. Key responsibilities involved the creation and organisation of JavaScript and TypeScript-based projects, and integration with third-party OAuth providers for all applications and services throughout the product.

Notable successes include a custom GraphQL API to federate several individual microservices, coordination of web SPA and other user-facing applications, and leading chapter/guild meetings for these projects.

Backend work focused on authentication/authorisation and API contracts between services to improve developer experiences and increase code confidence.

Software Engineer

November 2018 - July 2020

OakNorth

Full-stack development of backend microservices written in multiple languages and frontend single-page applications using TypeScript with React. This role included particular focus on engineering productivity and the evolution of internal tooling for internationalisation, static analysis, and API code generation.

Our team started with an initial 10 engineers and grew to over 100 with careful and considered hiring of prospective candidates.

Junior Developer

October 2017 – November 2018

Reach plc

Backend JavaScript development for native mobile and AMP web applications, deployed end-to-end and migrated to modern infrastructure using AWS ECS, Fargate, and CloudFront Lambda@Edge.

## Education

BA Mathematics and Computer Science

2012 - 2015

Keble College, University of Oxford

Notably including Object-Oriented Programming, Concurrent Programming, and Computer-Aided Formal Verification.

#### Other

Nuffield Science Bursary

Summer 2011

University of Surrey

Co-authored A quantitative assessment of using the Kinect for Xbox 360 for respiratory surface motion tracking and achieved a Gold CREST award.